Guide to the Bronx Teen Resource and Referral Network Records TAM.581
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Bronx Teen Resource and Referral Network Records
1983-1996
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Bronx Teen Resource and Referral Network
Cook, Yvonne
TAM.581
19 Linear Feet in 19 record cartons
The Bronx Teen Resource and Referral Network, formerly the Bronx Teen Pregnancy Network, was established in 1983. The Network functioned as a self-selected coalition of organizations, institutions, individuals. This collection includes materials related to the Network's activities and programs that provided education, support, and guidance to teenagers in the Bronx, particularly on the topics of pregnancy and sexually-transmitted diseases. There is also a substantial amount of material pertaining to fundraising.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Yvonne M. H. Cook on behalf of the Bronx Teen Resource and Referral Network in 1996. The accession number associated with this collection is 2011.062.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. Materials are in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Bronx Teen Resource and Referral Network, formerly the Bronx Teen Pregnancy Network, was established in February, 1983, as a result of the large number of teen pregnancies in the area. The Network functioned as a self-selected coalition of organizations, institutions, individuals, whose primary objectives were: the provision of information and referrals, identification of gaps in services, establishing a linkage system which would expedite appropriate and effective referrals and serve as a forum for resource sharing and joint planning and activities. The idea came from a group of social workers who decided to set up a Network in each of the five boroughs. The Bronx Teen Resource and Referral Network was the last one to survive.
The mission of the Bronx Teen Resource and Referral Network was to promote communication, networking, coalition-building and support among service providers and youth; and serve as a resource for the provision of education, cultural enrichment, research, technical assistance in support of service needs of young adults. Information and referrals, resource sharing, delivery and coordination of services, education, training, and advocacy are major goals of the Network. They had a quarterly newsletter that was tied to the information given at the Network meetings.
The Bronx Teen Resource and Referral Network closed in January 1996 because of lack of funding.
Scope and Content Note
This collection consists of the records of the Bronx Teen Resource and Referral Network from its founding in 1983 to its closure in 1996. The largest portion of the collection relates to the organization's unceasing search for funds (contracts, grants, proposals, and related material). However, there is also significant coverage of the Network's activities and programs that provided education, support, and guidance to teenagers in the Bronx, particularly on the topics of pregnancy and sexually-transmitted diseases. The files of executive director Agnes Cooper Dennis are especially well-represented, as is the Better Bronx for Youth program.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted. Born-digital materials have not been transferred and may not be available to researchers. Researchers may request access copies. To request that material be transferred, or if you are unsure if material has been transferred, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Teenage pregnancy |z New York (State) |z New York.; Sexually transmitted diseases |z New York (State) |z New York.; AIDS (Disease) -- New York (State) -- New York.; Substance abuse |z New York (State) |z New York.; Teenage mothers |z New York (State) |z New York.; Cook, Yvonne; Manhattan Teen Pregnancy Network; Dennis, Agnes Cooper; Better Bronx for Youth; Staten Island Teen Pregnancy Network; Brooklyn Teen Pregnancy Network; Cook, Yvonne; Queens Teen Pregnancy Network; Bronx Teen Resource and Referral Network; Bronx Teen Pregnancy Network
- Inventory
  - Fundraising, Grant and Project Proposals, Department of Youth Services Contracts and Proposals, Community Development Agency Contract, early 1980s-early 1990s (Box 1)
  - Assistance Rendered and Referrals Made (records with full name or address of clients destroyed for privacy reasons), Grant and Project Proposals, Outreach, Finances, and Committees, late 1980s-early 1990s (Box 2)
  - Department of Youth Services and Youth Bureau Contracts, Other Grants, Contracts, and Proposals, late 1980s-early 1990s (Box 3)
  - Committees, Subject Files, Grant Application, Assistance Rendered and Referrals Made (records with full name or address of clients destroyed for privacy reasons), Files on Related Organizations, late 1980s-early 1990s (Box 4)
  - Subject Files, Memos, Correspondence, and Proposals, late 1980s-mid 1990s (Box 5)
  - Staff Meetings, Outgoing Correspondence, Finances, Committees, Quarterly Reports, Agenda for Children Tomorrow (ACT) Proposal, late 1980s-early 1990s (Box 6)
  - Staff Meetings, Memos, Fundraising, ACT Proposal, Correspondence, Citywide Teen Pregnancy Network Planning, late 1980s-early 1990s (Box 7)
  - Citywide Teen Pregnancy Network Planning, Project Proposals, United Way Community Achievement Project in the Schools (CAPS), early 1990s (Box 8)
  - Grant and Project Proposals, Committees, Staff Meetings, Files on Related Organizations (especially the other NYC teen pregnancy networks), late 1980s-early 1990s (Box 9)
  - Citywide Teen Pregnancy Network Planning, Youth Leadership/Mentorship Program, Subject Files, late 1980s-early 1990s (Box 10)
  - Better Bronx for Youth Project Files, Staff Meetings, and Finances`, 1987-1989 (Box 11)
  - Better Bronx for Youth Project Files, Borough-Wide Conference Files (including audio cassettes of workshops), staff meetings (audio cassette recordings), mid 1980s-1990 (Box 12)
  - Department of Youth Services Proposals and Contracts, Correspondence, Finances, and Annual Reports, late 1980s-1994 (Box 13)
  - Committees, Finances, Student Surveys, Youth Bureau Proposal and Reports, and Material for Newsletter, mid 1980s-1990 (Box 14)
  - Material for Newsletter, Agnes Cooper Dennis (Executive Director) Subject Files (mostly on related organizations), 1988-1994 (Box 15)
  - Agnes Cooper Dennis (Executive Director) Correspondence (also includes memos) and Subject Files and Board of Directors (includes minutes), late 1980s-mid 1990s (Box 16)
  - Board of Directors, Reports, Meetings, Conferences, Memos, New York State Department of Social Services Contract, and Better Bronx for Youth Project Files, 1988-1994 (Box 17)
  - Better Bronx for Youth Project Files, Board of Directors, and Subcontractors, 1986-1994 (Box 18)
  - Audio Cassettes of Meetings and Events and Fifty-one floppy disks (5 1/4'') of Contracts and Other Materials, early-mid 1990s (Box 19)